welcome back to 6 SZ row 99 artificial
欢迎回到6 SZ排 99人工
general intelligence today we have Ilya
今天一般情报我们有伊利亚
sutskever co-founder and research
sutskever联合创始人和研究
director of open AI he started in the
开放AI的主任 他开始了
amel group in Toronto Geoffrey Hinton
多伦多杰弗里·辛顿的 阿梅尔集团
then at Stanford with an jiaying
然后在斯坦福大学和jiaying
co-founded DNN research for three years
共同创立了DNN研究 三年
as a research scientist at Google brain
作为谷歌大脑的研究科学家
and finally co-founded open AI citations
最后共同创立了开放的AI引用
aren't everything
不是一切
but they do indicate impact and his work
但它们确实表明了影响和他的工作
recent work in the past five years has
最近五年来的工作有了
been cited over forty six thousand times
被引用超过 四万 六千次
he has been the key creative intellect
他一直是关键的创造性智慧
and driver behind some of the biggest
和一些最大的背后的司机
breakthrough ideas in deep learning and
深度学习中的突破性思想
artificial intelligence ever
人工智能永远
so please welcome Ilya alright thanks
所以请欢迎伊利亚，谢谢
for the introduction Lex
为了介绍Lex
alright thanks for coming to my talk I
好的，谢谢你来我的演讲
will tell you about some work we've done
会告诉你 我们做过的 一些工作
over the past year on on meta learning
在过去的一年中，关于元学习
and software open AI and before I dive
和软件打开AI之前和我潜水
into some of the more technical details
进入一些更具技术性的细节
of the work I want to spend a little bit
工作我想 花一点点
of time talking about deep learning and
时间谈论深度学习和
why it works at all in the first place
为什么它在所有工作摆 在首位
which I think it's actually not a
我认为它实际上 不是一个
self-evident saying that they should
不言而喻的说他们应该
work one fact it's actually a fact it's
工作一个事实，它实际上是一个事实
a mathematical theory that you can prove
你可以证明的数学理论
is that if you could find the shortest
如果 你能找到最短的那个
program the does very very well on your
程序在 你 的方面做得 非常好
data then you will achieve the best
然后你会获得最好的数据
generalization possible with a little
一点点可以概括
bit of modification you can turn it into
你可以把它变成一点修改
a precise theorem
一个精确的定理
and on a very intuitive level it's easy
而且在非常直观的层面上很容易
to see what it should be the case if you
看看你应该如何 做到这一点
have some data and you're able to find a
有一些数据，你就能够 找到 一个
shorter program which generates this
产生这个的更短的程序
data then you've essentially extracted
数据，然后你基本上提取
all the all conceivable regularity from
所有可以想象的规律性
this data into your program and then you
这些数据进入你的程序 ，然后 你
can use these objects to make the best
可以使用这些对象来做到最好
predictions possible like if if you have
可能的预测，如果你有
data which is so complex but there is no
数据如此复杂 但没有
way to express it as a shorter program
把它表达 为一个较短的程序的方式
then it means that your data is totally
那意味着你的数据是完全的
random there is no way to extract any
随机没有办法提取任何
regularity from it whatsoever now there
现在在那里的 任何 规律性
is little known mathematical theory
鲜为人知的数学理论
behind this and the proofs of these
这背后的证据和这些证明
statements actually not even that hard
声明实际上甚至没 那么难
but the one minor slight disappointment
但是一点轻微的失望
is that it's actually not possible at
是的 ，它实际上是 不可能的
least given today's tools and
至少给出今天的工具和
understanding to find the best short
理解找到最好的短片
program that explains or generates or
解释或生成的程序或
solves your problem given your data this
根据您的数据 解决您的 问题
problem is computationally intractable
问题在计算上是难以处理的
the space of all programs is a very
所有节目的空间都是非常的
nasty space small changes to your
讨厌的空间小变化你的
program result in massive changes in the
程序导致了大量的变化
behavior of the program as it should be
该 程序 的行为， 因为它应该是
it makes sense you have a loop you
你有一个循环你是有道理的
change the inside of the loop of course
改变航向 的环的内侧
you get something totally different so
你得到的东西完全不同，所以
the space of programs is so hard at
程序的空间是这么难
least given what we know today search
至少考虑到我们今天所知道的搜索
there seems to be completely off the
似乎完全 脱离了
table well if we give up on shorts on
表好，如果我们放弃 短裤
short programs what about small circuits
简短的程序如何关于小电路
well it turns out that we are lucky it
事实证明我们 很 幸运
turns out that when it comes to small
事实证明，当涉及到小
circuits you can just find the best
您可以找到最好的电路
small circuits circuits that solves the
小电路电路 ， 解决了
problem using back propagation and this
使用反向传播 ，但此 问题
is the miraculous fact on which the rest
是其余的神奇事实
of AI stands it is the fact but then you
人工智能认为这是事实，但后来你
have a circuit and you impose
有一个电路， 你强加
constraints on your circuits on your
对你电路的限制
circuit using data you can find the way
电路使用数据你可以找到方法
to satisfy these constraints these
为了满足 这些 约束条件 ，这些
constraints using that problem by
使用该问题 的约束
iteratively making small changes
迭代地做出微小的 改变
to the base of your neural network until
到你的 神经 网络的基础， 直到
its predictions satisfy the data what
它的预测满足了数据的要求
this means is that the computational
这意味着计算
problem that so the back propagation is
问题， 即 这样 的 反向传播 是
extremely profound it is circuit search
非常深刻的是电路搜索
now we know that you can solve it solve
现在我们知道 你可以解决 它
it always but you can solve it sometimes
它总是但你有时可以解决它
and you can solve it at those times
你可以在这些时间解决它
where we have a practical data set it is
我们有一个实际的数据集 是
easy to design artificial data sets for
易于设计人工数据集
which you cannot find the best neural
你找不到最好的神经
network but in practice that seems to be
网络，但在实践中似乎是
not a problem you can think of training
你可以想到 训练 不是 问题
a neural network as solving a neural
神经网络解决神经网络问题
equation in many cases where you have a
在许多情况下，你有一个方程式
large number of equation terms like this
大量 方程而言是这样 的
f of X I theta equals y I so you got
西娅的f等于我，所以你得到了
your parameters and they represent all
你的参数 ，他们代表所有
your degrees of freedom and you use
你的自由度和 你使用
gradient descent to push the information
梯度下降推动信息
from these equations into the parameters
从这些方程式进入参数
satisfy them all and you can see that
满足他们所有 ，你可以看到
the neural network let's say one with 50
神经网络让我们说一个50
layers is basically a parallel computer
层基本上是一台并行计算机
that is given 50 time steps to run and
这给了50个时间步骤来运行和
you can do quite a lot with a 15 with 50
你可以 用15和50 来做很多事情
time steps of a very very powerful
时间步骤非常强大
massively parallel computer so for
大规模并行计算机
example I do I think it is not widely
我认为它并不广泛
known that you can learn to sort sort n
已知你可以学习排序n
n bit numbers using a modestly sized
使用适度大小的位数
neural network with just two hidden
神经网络只有两个隐藏
layers which is not bad it's not
不坏的层也不是
self-evident especially since we've been
不言而喻， 特别是自从我们去过以来
taught that sorting requires log n
教导说排序需要log n
parallel steps with the neural network
神经网络的并行步骤
you can sort successful using only two
你可以只用两个来成功排序
parallel steps so there's some things
并行步骤所以有一些事情
like an arm is going on now these are
就像手臂 正在进行中这些都是
parallel steps of threshold threshold
阈值阈值的并行步骤
neurons so they're doing a little bit
神经元， 所以 他们 做了一点点
more work let's answer to the mystery
更多的工作 让我们回答这个谜
but if you've got 50 such layers you can
但如果你 有50个这样的层， 你可以
do quite a bit of logic quite a bit of
做相当多 的 逻辑 相当多的
reasoning all inside the neural network
在 神经网络中推理所有内容
and that's why it works
这就是为什么它有效
given the data we are able to find the
根据我们 能够找到的数据
best neural network and because the
最好的神经网络，因为
neural network is deep because it can
神经网络很深，因为它可以
run computation inside of its act inside
在其内部运行计算
of its layers the best neural network is
它的层是最好的神经网络
worth finding because that's really what
值得一试， 因为那真的是什么
you need you need something you need the
你需要你需要的东西
model class which is worth optimizing
值得优化的模型类
but it also needs to be optimizable and
但它也需要是可以优化的
deep neural networks satisfy both of
深度神经网络 满足两者
these constraints and this is why
这些约束和这就是原因
everything works this is the basis on
一切正常，这是基础
which everything else resides now I want
现在我想要的其他所有东西
to talk a little bit about reinforcement
谈谈 加固
learning so reinforcement learning is a
学习如此强化学习是一种
framework it's a framework of evaluating
框架它是 一个评估框架
agents in their ability to achieve goals
代理人在实现目标的能力
and complicated stochastic environments
和复杂的随机环境
you've got an agent which is plugged
你有一个插件代理
into an environment as shown in the
进入如图所示的环境
figure right here and for any given
在这里和任何 给定的数字
agent you can simply run it many times
代理你可以简单地运行 它多次
and compute its average reward now the
现在 计算它的平均 奖励
thing that's interesting about the
这很有趣 的事儿
reinforcement learning framework is that
强化学习框架就是这样
there exist interesting useful
有趣的有用
reinforcement learning algorithms the
强化 学习算法
framework existed for a long time it
框架存在了很长时间了
became interesting once we realized that
一旦我们 意识到这一点就变得有趣
good algorithms exist now these are
现在 存在好的算法
there are perfect algorithms but they
有完美的算法， 但他们
are good enough to do interesting things
足够好做有趣的事情
and all you want the mathematical
而你想要的只是数学
problem is one where you need to
问题是你需要的地方
maximize the expected reward now one
现在最大化预期奖励一个
important way in which the reinforcement
加固的重要方式
learning framework is not quite complete
学习框架不是很完整
is that it assumes that the reward is
是假设 奖励是
given by the environment you see this
由环境给出你看到这个
picture the agent sends an action while
图片代理发送动作的同时
the reward sends it an observation in a
奖励 发送给他一个观察
both the observation and the reward
观察 和奖励
backwards that's what the environment
倒退那就是环境
communicates back
沟通回来
the way in which this is not the case in
在此不在 的情况下的方式
the real world is that we figure out
现实世界是 我们弄明白的
what the reward is from the observation
从观察中获得的回报是什么
we reward ourselves we are not told
我们奖励自己， 我们不被告知
environment doesn't say hey here's some
环境不说嘿这里有些
negative reward it's our interpretation
否定奖励是我们的解释
over census that lets us determine what
人口普查 让我们 确定了 什么
the reward is and there is only one real
奖励是，只有一个真实的
true reward in life and this is
生命中的真正回报就是这样
existence or nonexistence and everything
存在或不存在以及一切
else is a corollary of that so well what
否则就是那么好的必然结果
should our agent be you already know the
如果我们的代理人你已经知道了
answer should be a neural network
答案应该是一个神经网络
because whenever you want to do
因为每当你想做的时候
something dense it's going to be a
密集的东西， 它将成为一个
neural network and you want the agent to
神经网络， 你想要代理
map observations to actions so you let
将观察结果映射到动作让你放手
it be parametrized with a neural net and
它用神经网络进行参数化
you apply learning algorithm so I want
你应用学习算法，所以我想要
to explain to you how reinforcement
向你 解释 如何加固
learning works this is model free
学习作品这是免费模型
reinforcement learning the reinforcement
强化学习强化
learning has actually been used in
学习实际上 已被用于
practice everywhere but it's also deeply
到处练习，但也很深入
it's very robust it's very simple it's
它非常强大，非常简单
also not very efficient so the way it
它的效率也不是很高效
works is the following this is literally
作品被以下 这是字面上
the one sentence description of what
什么的一句话描述
happens in short try something new add
总之， 尝试一些新的补充
randomness directions and compare the
随机方向和比较
result to your expectation if the result
如果结果你的期望结果
surprises you if you find that the
如果你发现了，你会感到惊讶
results exceeded your expectation then
业绩超出 你的期望 ，然后
change your parameters to take those
更改您的参数以获取这些参数
actions in the future that's it this is
这就是未来的 行动
the fool idea of reinforcement learning
强化学习的愚蠢想法
try it out see if you like it and if you
尝试看看你是否 喜欢它 ，如果你 喜欢它
do do more of that in the future and
在未来做更多的事情
that's it that's literally it this is
就是这就是它的确如此
the core idea now it turns out it's not
现在的核心理念却证明并非如此
difficult to formalize mathematically
难以用数学形式化
but this is really what's going on
但这确实是在发生什么
if in a neural network in a regular
如果在常规的神经网络 中
neural network like this you might say
你可能会说这样的神经网络
okay what's the goal
好的 ，目标是什么
you run the neural network you get an
你运行你得到 的 神经网络
answer you compare it to the desired
回答 你把它 与想要的 比较
answer and whatever difference you have
回答和你有什么不同
between those two you send it back
在这两者之间你发 回来
to change the neural network that's
改变神经网络
supervised line in reinforcement
加固中的监督线
learning you run in your own network you
学习你在你自己的网络中运行 你
add a bit of randomness to your action
为您的操作添加一些随机性
and then if you like the result your
如果你 喜欢结果你的
randomness turns into the desired target
随机性变成了期望的目标
in effect so that's it trivial now math
实际上这就是现在 数学上 的琐碎
exists without explaining what these
存在而不解释这些
equations mean the point is not really
方程式 意味着这一点 并非如此
to derive them but just to show that
推导 它们只是为了证明这一点
they exist there are two classes of
他们存在有两类
reinforcement learning algorithms one of
强化学习算法之一
them is the policy gradient where
它们是政策梯度所在
basically what you do is that you take
基本上你所做的就是 你采取的
this expression right there the sum of
这种表达在那里 的总和
expected we work the sum of rewards and
我们希望我们 能够获得奖励和奖金
it just crunched through the derivatives
它只是通过衍生 嘎吱嘎吱
you expand the terms iran you do some
你扩展你做的一些伊朗的条款
algebra and you get a derivative and
代数，你得到一个 衍生物
miraculously the derivative has exactly
奇迹般地，衍生物完全正确
the form that i told you which is try
我告诉你 的 形式 是尝试
some actions and if you like them
一些行动，如果你喜欢他们
increase the log probability of the
增加日志的概率
actions that we truly follows from the
让大家真正从如下行动
math it's very nice when the intuitive
数学 这是非常好的直观
explanation has a one-to-one
解释有一对一
correspondence to what you get in the
对应于你得到的东西
equation even though you have to take my
即使你 必须采取我的方程式
word for it if you are not familiar with
如果你不熟悉的话
it that's that equation at the top now
这就是 现在 顶部 的 等式
there is a different class of
有一个不同的类
reinforcement learning algorithms which
强化学习算法
is a little bit more difficult to
有点困难
explain it's called the Q learning based
解释它被称为 基于Q学习
algorithms they are a bit less stable a
算法它们有点不太稳定了
bit more sample efficient and it has the
更高效的样品，它有
property that it can learn not only from
它不仅可以从中学到的财产
the data generated by the actor but from
演员生成的数据， 但来自
any other data as well so it has it has
任何其他数据，所以它有它
some rope but it has different
一些绳索，但它有不同
robustness profile which would be a
鲁棒性概况 ，这将是一个
little bit important but it's only going
有点 重要，但它只是去
to be a technicality so yeah this is the
是 技术性 所以是的，这是
own policy of policy distinction but
自己的政策区分政策但是
it's a little bit technical so if you
这是一个 有点技术，所以如果你
find this hard to understand don't worry
发现这很难理解 不用担心
about it if you already know this then
关于它， 如果你已经知道这一点
you already know it so now what's the
你已经知道了，现在是什么 了
potential for enforcement learning
执法学习的潜力
wasn't it promised what is it actually
是不是它承诺 实际上 是什么
why should we be excited about it
我们为什么要 对它感到兴奋
now there are two reasons the
现在有两个原因了
reinforcement learning algorithms of
强化学习算法
today already useful and interesting and
今天已经有用，有趣 ，
especially if you have a really good
特别是如果你真的 很好
simulation of your world you could train
模拟你可以训练的世界
agents to do lots of interesting things
代理商做了很多有趣的事情
but what's really exciting is if you can
但真正令人兴奋的是，如果可以的话
build a super amazing sample efficient
构建一个超级惊人的样本高效
out of reinforcement learning algorithm
超出强化学习算法
we just give it a tiny amount of data
我们只给它一些数据
and the algorithm just crunches through
而算法只是匆匆而过
it and extracts every bit of entropy out
它并提取出每一点熵
of it in order to learn in the fastest
为了 学 得最快
way possible now today our algorithms
今天我们的算法可行的方式
are not particularly efficient they are
它们并不是特别有效
data inefficient but as our field keeps
数据效率低下，但我们的领域仍然存在
making progress this will change next I
取得进展这 将改变我的下一步
want to dive into the topic of meta
想深入 探讨元 的 主题
learning the goal of meta learning so
学习元学习的目标
meta learning is a beautiful idea that
元学习是一个美丽的想法，
doesn't really work but it kind of works
没有真正起作用，但 它有点工作
and it's really promising too it's
它真的很有前途
another promising idea so what's the
另一个有希望的想法是什么呢
dream we have some learning algorithms
我们有一些学习算法
perhaps you could use those learning
也许你可以使用那些学习
algorithms in order to learn to learn
算法， 以 学习学习
I'd be nice if we could learn to learn
如果我们能 学会学习， 我会很高兴
so how would you do that you will take a
所以你会怎么做，你 会采取一个
system which you train it not on one
你不训练它的系统
task but on many tasks and you ask you
任务，但在许多任务，你问你
that it learns to solve these tasks
它学会了解决这些任务
quickly and that may actually be enough
很快，这可能就足够了
so here's how it looks like here's how
所以这里是它的外观像这里是 如何
most traditional metal earning look
最传统的金属赚钱外观
works like it looks like you have a
看起来像你有一个
model which is a big neural network what
模型是一个很大的神经网络
what you do is that you treat every
你做什么， 是 你对待每一个
instead of training cases you have
而不是训练案例
training tasks and instead of test cases
培训任务而不是测试用例
you have test tasks so your input may be
你有测试任务所以你的输入 可能是
instead of just your current test case
而 不仅仅是 当前 的 测试案例
it would be all the information about
这将是 关于的 所有 信息
the new T above the test tasks plus the
新T 超过 测试任务加上
test case and you'll try to output the
测试用例，你会尝试输出
prediction reaction for that test case
该测试用例的预测反应
so basically you say yeah I'm going to
所以基本上你说是的我会去
give you your ten examples as part of
给你十个例子 作为一部分
your input to your model figure out how
您对模型的输入会弄清楚 如何
to make the best use of them it's a
为了充分利用它们，它是一个
really
真
straightforward idea u-turn the neural
直截了当的想法 转向 神经
network into the learning algorithm by
网络进入学习算法
turning a training task into a training
将培训任务转变为培训
case so training to ask a constraining
这样的情况下训练要求的约束
case this is meta learning just one
这是元学习中的一个
sentence and so they've been several
这句话他们已经好几个了
success stories which I I think are very
我认为非常成功的故事
interesting one of the success stories
成功案例 的一个 有趣
of meta learning is learning to
元学习是学习
recognize characters quickly so they've
他们很快就认出了人物
been a dataset
是一个数据集
produced by MIT by lake corral and this
麻省理工学院由湖畜栏制作而成
is a data set we have a large number of
是一个我们拥有大量数据集的数据集
different handwritten characters and
不同的手写字符和
people have been able to train extremely
人们已经能够 极其训练
strong meta learning system for this
这个强大的元学习系统
desk another successful another very
另一个非常成功的另一个
successful example of meta learning is
元学习的成功范例 是
in that of neural architecture search by
在神经结构搜索中
is openly from google where they found
他们发现谷歌是公开的
neural architecture that solved one
解决了一个的神经结构
problem well small problem and then you
问题好小问题然后你
could generalize and then if you
可以概括，然后 如果你
successfully solve large problems as
成功解决了大问题
well so this is the kind of the the
也因此，这是 那种 对 的
small number of bits meta learning is
元学习的位数很少
that when you learn the architecture or
当你学习建筑或者
maybe even learn a program small program
甚至可能学习 一个程序小程序
or learning algorithm which you apply to
或您申请的学习算法
new tasks so this is the other way of
新的任务，所以这是另一种方式
doing meta learning so anyway but the
无论如何做元学习但是
point is what's happening what's really
重点是发生了什么 真的
happening in meta learning in most cases
在大多数情况下，在元学习中发生
is that you turn a training task into a
是你把训练任务变成了一个
training case and pretend this is
训练案例并假装这是
totally normal
完全正常
normal deep learning that's it this is
这 是正常的深度学习
the entirety of meta learning everything
整个meta学习一切
else suggests minor details next I wanna
其他建议接下来 我想要的 细节
dive in so now that I've finished the
现在我已经完成了这项工作
introduction section I want to start
介绍部分我想开始
discussing different work by different
讨论不同的工作
people from opening I and I want to
从打开 我的人，我想
start by talking about hindsight
首先谈谈后见之明
experience replay it's been a large
体验重播它是一个很大的
effort by and recurvature all to develop
努力和重新发展所有的发展
a learning algorithm for reinforcement
加强 学习算法
learning
学习
that doesn't solve just one task but it
这不仅解决了一个任务，而且解决了它
solves many tasks and it learns to make
解决了很多任务，并且学会了
use of its experience in a much more
使用它的经验更多
efficient way and I want to discuss one
有效的方式，我想讨论一个
problem in reinforcement learning it's
加强学习它的问题
actually I guess a set of problems which
实际上我猜是一组问题
all related to each other at one really
所有 在 一个 相互关联的 真
important thing you need to learn to do
你需要 学会做重要的事
is to explore you're in that you start
是为了探索 你， 因为你开始
out in an environment you don't know
在你 不认识 的环境中
what to do what do you do so one very
做什么你这么做
important thing that has to happen is
必须发生的重要事情是
that you must get rewards from time to
你必须 从时间 奖励
time if you try something and you don't
时间， 如果你尝试的 东西，但你没有
get rewards then how can you learn so
得到奖励然后你怎么能 这样学习
said that's the kind of the crux of the
说的那种的症结
problem how do you learn and relatedly
问题你如何学习和相关的
is there any way to meaningfully benefit
有没有办法有意义地受益
from your ex from the experience from
来自你的前经验
your attempts to from from your failures
你 的失败 尝试
if you try to achieve a goal and you
如果你试图实现目标而你
fail can you still learn from it you
失败你还能从中吸取教训 吗？
tell you instead of asking your
告诉你而不是问 你的
algorithm to achieve a single goal you
算法实现单一目标你
want to learn a policy that can achieve
想要学习可以实现的政策
a very large family of goals for example
一个 非常大的家庭的目标， 例如
instead of reaching one state you want
而不是达到 你想要的 一个状态
to learn a policy that reaches every
学习达到每个人的政策
state of your system and what's the
你的系统的状态和它是什么
implication anytime you do something you
任何时候你做某事都意味着什么
achieve some state so let's suppose you
达到某种状态让我们假设你
say I want to achieve state a I try my
说我想实现状态我试试我的
best and I end up achieving state B I
最好，我最终实现状态BI
can either conclude well that was
可以总结得那么好
disappointing I haven't learned almost
令人失望我 几乎 没有学到什么
anything I'm still have no idea how to
任何我仍然 不知道如何做的 事情
cheat how to achieve state aid but
欺骗如何实现国家 援助但是
alternatively I can say well wait a
或者我可以说等一下
second I've just reached a perfectly
第二， 我刚刚达到 完美
good state which is B can I learn how to
好的状态是B，我可以学习如何
achieve state B from my attempt to
从我的尝试到达状态B.
achieve state a an answer is yes you can
实现状态答案是肯定的
and it just works and I just want to
它只是工作， 我只是想
point out this is the one case there is
指出这是 一个案例
a small subtlety here which may be
这可能是一个小小的微妙
interesting to those of you who are very
对你们这些非常有趣的人来说很有意思
familiar with on Part B the distinction
熟悉 B部分的区别
between on policy and off policy when
政策 与政策之间的关系
you try to achieve a you are on you're
你试图实现一个你在你身边
doing on policy learning for
做政策学习
reaching the state a but you're doing
到达州，但你正在做
off policy learning for it in the state
在州内取消政策学习
be because you would take different
因为你会采取不同的方式
actions if you would actually try to
如果你真的想要的话
reach they'd be so that's why it's very
到达他们就是这样，这就是它的原因
important that the algorithm you use
你使用的算法很重要
here can support of policy learning but
这里可以支持政策学习但是
that's a minor technicality at the crux
这是关键问题的一个小技术问题
the crux of the idea is you make the
这个想法的关键是你做的
problem easier by ostensibly making it
从表面上看它的问题就更容易了
harder by training a system which can
通过训练可以的系统更难
which aspires to reach to learn to reach
渴望达到 学习达到的目标
every state to learn to achieve every
每个州要学会实现每一个目标
goal to learn to master its environment
学习掌握环境的目标
in general you build a system which
一般来说， 你建立一个系统
always learn something it learns from
总是学习它从中学到的东西
success as well as from failure because
成功以及失败因为
if it tries to do one thing one thing
如果它试图做一件事一件事
and it does something else
它还有别的东西
it now has training data for how to
它现在有关于如何的训练数据
achieve that something else I want to
实现我想要的其他东西
show you a video of how this thing works
向您 展示这个 东西 是 如何 工作 的视频
in practice so one challenge in
在实践中这样一个挑战
reinforcement learning systems is the
强化学习系统就是 这样
need to shape the reward so what does it
需要塑造 奖励 所以它是什么
mean
意思
it means that at the beginning of the
它意味着在开始时
system at the start of learning then the
系统在学习之初就开始了
system doesn't know much it will
系统不太了解它
probably not achieve your goal and so
可能 没有实现你的目标
it's important that you design your
你设计你的设计很重要
reward function to give it gradual
奖励功能让它渐进
increments to make it smooth and
增量，使之光滑
continuous so that even when the system
连续使即使在系统
is not very good it achieves the goal
实现目标 并不是 很好
now if you give your state your system a
现在如果你给你的州你的系统了
very sparse reward where the reward is
奖励是非常稀疏的奖励
achieved only when you reach a final
只有当你进入决赛时才能实现
state then it becomes very hard for
状态，那么 它 变得非常难
normal reinforcement learning algorithms
正常强化学习算法
to solve a problem because naturally you
解决问题因为很自然
never get the reward so you never learn
从来没有获得奖励，所以你永远不会学到
no reward means no learning but here
没有奖励意味着没有学习，但在这里
because you learn from failure as well
因为你从失败中学习， 以及
as from success
从成功
this is this problem simply doesn't
这个问题根本就没有
occur and so this is this is nice I
发生，所以这 是， 这 是很好的我
think you know let's let's look at the
想你知道让我们看看吧
videos a little bit more like it's nice
视频有点像它很好
how this is it confidently and
这是多么自信和
energetically moves the little green
精力充沛地移动小绿
buck to its target and here's another
屈服于它的目标， 这是另一个
one
一
you
您
okay so we can skip the it works on
好的，所以我们可以跳过它的工作原理
spawn on the face if you do it on
如果你做的 话会 在 脸上 产卵
physical robot as well but we can skip
物理机器人，但我们可以跳过
it so I think the point is that the
它，所以我认为这一点是 ，
hindsight experience replay algorithm is
事后体验重播算法是
directionally correct because you want
因为你想要的方向正确
to make use of all your data and not
使用所有数据而不是
only a small fraction of it now one huge
现在只有一小部分 是 巨大的
question is where do you get the high
问题是你从哪里获得高价
level states where do the high level
电平状态在哪里高水平
states come from because in the work of
国家来自于因为在工作 中
showing you so far
到目前为止向你展示
the system is asked to achieve low level
要求系统达到低水平
States so I think one thing it will
国家所以我认为 它会有 一件事
become very important for this kind
成为这种非常重要
approaches is representation learning
方法是表达学习
and unsupervised learning figure out
和无监督学习弄不清
what are the rights what are the right
权利是什么权利
states what's the state space of goals
陈述 目标 的状态空间是什么
that's worth achieving now I want to go
这是值得实现的，我想去
through some real meta learning results
通过一些真实的元学习 结果
and I'll show you a very simple way of
我会告诉 你一个非常简单的方法
doing seem to reel from simulation to
做似乎 从模拟到卷轴
the physical robot with meta learning
具有元学习的物理机器人
and this is where my pain growl was an a
这就是 我痛苦咆哮的地方
and encouraged a really nice intern
并鼓励一个非常好的实习生
project in 2017 so I think we can agree
2017年的项目，所以我认为我们可以同意
that in the domain of robotics it would
在机器人技术的领域 它会
be nice if you could train your policy
如果你能训练你的政策，那就好了
in simulation and then somehow this
在模拟，然后以某种方式
knowledge would carry over to the
知识会延续到
physical robot now we can build we can
物理 机器人现在我们可以建立我们可以
build simulators that are okay but they
构建模拟器， 但它们没问题
can never perfectly match the real world
永远无法与现实世界完美匹配
unless you want to have an insanely slow
除非 你想要一个疯狂的慢
simulator and the reason for that is
模拟器及其 原因 是
that it turns out that simulating freaky
事实证明，模拟 怪异
simulating contacts is super hard and I
模拟联系人是非常困难的我
heard somewhere correct me if I'm wrong
如果我错了，我会在某处找到正确的答案
that simulating friction is np-complete
该 模拟摩擦是NP完全问题
I'm not sure but it's like stuff like
我不确定，但它就像是喜欢的东西
that so your simulation is just not
所以你的模拟就是这样
going to match reality there will be
要符合现实会有
some resemblance but that's it
一些相似之处，但就是这样
how can we
我们怎么样？
address this problem and I want to show
解决这个问题， 我想表明
you one simple idea so let's say one
你有一个简单的想法让我们说一个
thing once one thing that would be nice
事情曾经是一件好事
is that if you could learn a policy
如果你能 学习一项政策，那就是
learn a policy that would quickly adapt
学习一种 能够快速 适应 的政策
itself to the real world well if you
如果你自己对现实世界 很好
want to learn a policy that can quickly
想要快速学习一项政策
adapt we need to make sure it has
适应我们需要确保它有
opportunities to adapt during training
在培训期间适应的机会
time so what do we do instead of solving
时间，让我们做什么 ， 而不是 解决
a problem in just one simulator we add a
在短短的一个模拟器 的 问题 。 我们添加
huge amount of variability to the
巨大的可变性
simulator we say we will randomize the
模拟器我们说我们会随机化
friction so we will randomize the masses
摩擦，所以我们 将随机化群众
the length of the different objects and
不同物体的长度和
their I guess M dimensions so you try to
他们我猜M尺寸所以你 试着
randomize physics they simulate in lots
随机化他们模拟的物理学
of different ways and then importantly
不同的 方式，然后重要的是
you don't tell the policy how you
你不告诉政策你是怎么做的
randomized it so what is it going to do
将它随机化，以便它能做什么
then you take your policy and you put it
然后你采取你的政策， 你把它
in an environment then says well this is
在一个环境中， 然后说这是
really really tough I don't know what
真的很难 我不知道是什么
the masses are and I don't know what the
群众是，我不 知道是什么
frictions are I need to try things out
摩擦是 我需要尝试的事情
and figure out what the friction is as I
并 找出与我一样的摩擦力
get it responses from the environment so
把它从环境响应，这样
you're building you you learn a certain
你正在建立你，你学到了一定的知识
degree of adaptability into the policy
对政策的适应程度
and it actually works
它 确实有效
let's want to show you this is what
让我们想告诉你这是什么
happens when you just strain a policy in
当你刚刚 采取政策 时会发生
simulation and deploy it on the physical
模拟并将其部署在物理上
robot and here the goal is to bring the
机器人和这里的目标是 使
hockey puck towards the red dot and you
冰球朝着红点和你
will see that it will struggle and the
会看到它会挣扎和
reason it struggles is because of the
它挣扎的原因是因为
systematic differences between the
之间的系统性差异
simulator and the real physical robot so
模拟器和真实物理机器人如此
I can even the basic movement is
我甚至可以基本运动
difficult for the policy because the
困难的， 因为政策
assumptions are violated so much so if
假设被违反了很多，如果
you do the training as I discussed we
你按照我的讨论进行训练
train a recurrent neural network policy
训练一个反复出现的神经网络政策
which learns to quickly infer properties
学会快速推断属性
of the simulator in order to accomplish
的模拟器，以实现
the task you can then give it the real
你可以把它赋予 真实 的任务
thing
事情
the real physics and it will do much
真正的物理学，它会做很多
better so now this is not a perfect
更好所以现在这不是一个完美的
technique but it's definitely very
技术， 但它 肯定非常
promising it's promising whenever you
承诺无论何时你都有希望
are able to sufficiently randomize the
能够 充分随机化
simulator so it's definitely very nice
模拟器所以它绝对非常好
to see the closed-loop nature of the
看到的闭环性质
policy you consider it would push the
你认为它 会推动政策
hockey puck and would correct it
冰球并将纠正它
very very gently to bring it to the goal
非常非常 温和地 把它带到目标
yeah so that that was cool so that was
是的，所以这很酷，所以那是
very that was a cool application of meta
这是一个很酷 的 meta 应用程序
learning I want to discuss one more
学习 我想讨论一个 更
application of meta learning which is
元学习的应用
learning a hierarchy of actions and this
学习的行动，这一个层次
was work done by France at all actually
实际上是法国完成的工作
kept in France the ancient who did it
留在法国的古代人做到了
was in high school I mean he wrote this
在高中我的 意思是他写了这个
paper so one thing that would be nice is
纸这么一两件事 ，将 是不错的
if reinforcement learning was
如果强化学习是
hierarchical if instead of simply taking
等级而不是简单地 采取
micro actions you've had some kind of
你曾经有过某种微观行为
little subroutines that you could deploy
你可以部署小子程序
maybe the term subroutine is a little
也许术语子程序有点
bit too crude but if you had some idea
有点太粗糙，但如果你有一些想法
of which action primitives are worth
哪些动作原语 值得
starting with now no one has been able
从现在开始，没有人能够
to to get actually like real value add
实际上就像真正的增值一样
from curricula reinforcement learning
从课程强化学习
yet so far all the really cool results
到目前为止所有 非常酷的结果
all the really convincing is also
所有真正令人信服的也是
reinforcement learning do not use it
强化学习不要使用它
that's because we haven't quite figured
那是 因为我们还没有想到
out what's the right way for
什么是正确的方法
reinforcement learning for her ocular
为她的 眼睛强化学习
reinforcement learning
强化学习
I just want to show you one very simple
我只想 告诉你一个 非常 简单
approach where you use meta-learning to
你使用 元学习的方法
learn to learn a hierarchy of actions so
学习如何学习行动的层次结构
here's what you do you have in this
这里是 你做什么 ，你 有这
specific work you have a certain yeah
你有一定的具体工作 是的
let's say you have a certain number of
假设你拥有一定数量 的
low-level primitives let's say you have
低级原语让我们说你有
two ten of them and you have a
其中两个 和你有一个
distribution of tasks and your goal is
任务的 分配 和你的目标 是
to learn low level primitives such that
学习 低级原语
when they are used inside a very brief
当他们在一个非常短暂的内部使用
run of some reinforcement learning
一些强化学习的运行
algorithm you will make as much progress
算法你会取得很大的进步
as possible so the idea is you want to
尽可能这样你想要的想法
get the greatest amount of progress you
获得进步的最大 数额 你
want to learn policies that result in
想了解导致政策
the great story you want to learn
你想要学习的伟大故事
primitives that result in the greatest
导致 最大的原语
amount of progress is possible when used
使用时的进度量是 可能
inside learning so this is a meta
内部学习所以这是一个元
learning setter because any distribution
学习二传手因为任何分布
of tasks and here we've had if we've had
任务的，在这里我们有，如果我们已经 有
a little maze here the distribution of a
这里有点迷宫 的分布
mazes and in this case the little bug
迷宫，在这种情况下是小虫子
learned three policies which move it in
学会了三项推动它的政策
its fixed direction and as a result of
它的固定 方向和结果
having this hierarchy you're able to
拥有这种层次结构你能够
solve problems really fast but only when
快速 解决 问题， 但 只有在
the hierarchy is correct
层次结构是正确的
so horican reinforcement learning is
所以 horican强化学习是
still working progress and this was an
仍在努力进步，这是一个
and this work is an interesting proof
这项工作是一个有趣的证明
point of how Haruko reinforcement could
Haruko加固可以如何
be like how heretical reinforcement
就像异端强化一样
learning could be like if it worked now
学习可能就像现在一样有效
I want to just spend one slide
我想只 花一张 幻灯片
addressing the limitations of high
解决高的局限性
capacity method learning the specific
能力 方法学习具体
limitation is that the training test
限制是训练 测试
distribution has to be equal to the test
分配必须等于测试
test distribution and I think this is a
测试分布，我 认为这是一个
real limitation because in reality you
真正的限制，因为 在现实中你
the new test that you want to learn do
要学会 做新的测试
in some ways being fundamentally
在某些方面从根本上来说
different from anything you've seen so
不同于你见过的任何东西
far so for example if you go to school
例如，如果你去学校
you learn lots of useful things but then
你学到 很多有用的东西 ，但随后
they go to work only a fraction of this
他们上班只是其中的 一小部分
of the things that you've learned
你学到的东西
carries over you need to learn if you
遗留下来 ，你需要学习
need quite a few more things from
需要相当多的 更多的事情
scratch so metal owning would struggle
划伤所以金属拥有会挣扎
with that because it really assumes that
因为它确实假定了这一点
the Train the training data is that the
火车上的训练 数据是 ，
distribution over the training task has
分配培训任务了
to be equal to the distribution of the
为 等于的分布
test tasks that's the limitation I think
测试任务是 我认为 的限制
that as we develop better algorithms for
因为我们开发了更好的算法
being robust when the test tasks outside
在外面的测试任务时保持健壮
of the distribution of the training
培训的分配
tasks the metal on would work much
金属 上的 任务 会 起作用
better now I want to talk about self
现在 我想 谈谈自我
play the links of play is a very cool
发挥游戏的环节是非常酷的
topic that's starting to get attention
开始引起注意的话题
only now and I want to start by
只是现在，我想开始
reviewing very old work called TD gammon
回顾一下名为TD gammon的非常古老的作品
it's back from all the way from 1992 so
它是从所有的方式回到1992 年 使
it's 26 years old now it was done by
现在它已经 26岁了
Jerry to cero so this work is really
杰里， 所以这项工作 真的很棒
incredible because it has so much
不可思议，因为它有这么多
relevance today what they did basically
今天他们基本上做了什么
they said okay let's take two neural
他们说好吧让我们采取两个神经
networks and let them let them play
网络，让他们让他们 玩
against each other let them play
相互对抗让他们发挥
backgammon against each other and let
步步高互相攻击，让
them in tray let them be trained
他们在托盘中让他们接受训练
particularly so it's a super-modern
特别是这是一个超现代的
approach and you would think this was a
方法，你会认为这是 一个
paper from 2017 except that then you
2017纸不同 的是 ，那么你
look at this plot it shows that you only
看看这个情节，它只显示你
have ten hidden units twenty hidden
有十个 隐藏的单位 二十个隐藏
units forty and eighty for the different
单位四十和八十为不同
M colors where you notice that the
M 颜色你注意到的地方
largest neural network works best so in
最大的神经网络效果最佳
some ways not much has changed and this
某些方面没有太大变化，这一点
is the evidence
是 证据
and in fact they were able to beat the
事实上他们 能够击败
world champion in backgammon and they
步步高和他们的世界冠军
were able to discover new strategies
能够发现新的策略
that the best human a backgammon players
那个最好的人类步步高玩家
weren't ever not noticed and they've
他们从来都没有注意过
determined that the strategy discovered
确定战略发现了
by TD gammon actually better
通过TD gammon 实际上更好
so that's pure self play with cue
所以这是纯粹的自我玩耍
learning which is which remained dormant
学习 哪些仍处于休眠状态
until the DQ and work with Atari mid
直到DQ并与 Atari mid合作
mind so now other examples of self play
现在，请记住其他自我玩耍的例子
include alphago zero which was able to
包括alphago零，这是能够
learn to beat the world champion and go
学会 击败世界 冠军而去
without using any external data
不使用任何外部数据
whatsoever another result of this vein
无论如何这种静脉的 另一个结果
is by open AI which is our dota 2 BOTS
是开放的AI，这是我们的dota 2 BOTS
which was able to build the world
这是能够 建立世界
champion on the 1v1 version of the game
1v1版游戏的冠军
and so I want to spend a little bit of
所以我想花一点点钱
time talking about the allure of self
时间谈论 自我 的 诱惑力
play and why I think it's exciting so
玩，为什么我认为这是令人兴奋的
one important problem that's a that
这是 一个重要的一个问题
that's that we must face as we try to
这是我们必须面对 ， 因为我们想
build truly intelligent systems is what
构建真正的智能系统是什么
is the task what are we actually
是我们实际上的任务
teaching the systems to do and one very
教导系统做一个非常好的
attractive attribute of self play is
自我发挥的吸引力属性是
that the agents create the environment
代理创建环境
by virtue of the agent acting in the
凭借代理人行事
environment the environment becomes
环境变得环境
difficult for the other agents and you
其他代理人 和你很难
can see here an example of an iguana
这里可以看到一只鬣蜥的例子
interacting with snakes that try to eat
蛇是试 吃 互动
it
它
unsuccessfully this time so we can see
这次没有成功， 所以我们可以看到
what will happen in a moment the iguana
鬣蜥会在一瞬间会发生什么
strains best and so the fact you have
最好的，所以你有这个事实
this arms race between the snakes and
这场蛇与蛇之间的军备竞赛
the iguana
绿鬣蜥
motivates their development potentially
可能激发他们的发展
without bound and this is what happens
没有约束， 这就是发生的事情
in effect in but in biological evolution
但在生物进化中却有效
now interesting work in this direction
现在这方面有趣的工作
was done in 1994 but Carl says there is
在1994年完成，但 卡尔说有
a really cool video on YouTube by Carl
卡尔 在YouTube上播放了一段非常酷的视频
seems you should check it out which
好像 你应该看看 哪个
really kind of shows all the work that
真有种显示了所有的工作，
he's done and here you have a little
他已经完成了，你在这里有一点点
competition between agents where you
您所在代理商之间的竞争
evolved both the behavior and their
演变 了行为和他们的行为
morphology when you when the agents is
当代理人是你时的形态
trying to gain possession of a green
试图获得绿色
cube and so you can see that the agents
多维数据集，所以你可以看到代理商
create the challenge for each other and
为彼此创造挑战
that's why they need to develop so one
这就是为什么他们需要 发展这么一个
thing that we did and this is work by
我们做的事情，这是工作
advance a little from open ai is we said
提前 一 点点 从开放 AI是我们说
okay well can we demonstrate some
好吧， 我们 可以 证明一些
unusual results in self play that would
自我发挥的不寻常结果
really convince us that there is
真的说服我们有
something there so what we did here is
东西 有那么我们在这里做 的
that we created a small a small ring and
我们创造了一个 小小的戒指和
you have these two humanoid figures and
你有这两个人形和
their goal is just to push each other
他们的目标只是互相推动
outside the ring and they don't know
环以外的 ，他们不知道
anything about wrestling they don't know
关于他们不知道的摔跤的任何事情
anything about standing your balance in
关于 保持平衡的任何事情
each other they don't know anything
他们彼此都不知道
about centers of gravity all they know
他们所知道的重心
is that if you don't do a good job then
如果你没有做好 那么
your competition is going to do a better
你的竞争对手会做得更好
job now one of the really attractive
现在的工作真正吸引人 的 地方 之一
things about self play is that you
关于自我玩耍的事情就是你
always have an opponent that's roughly
总是有一个粗略的对手
as good as you are in order to learn you
和你一样好，以便了解你
need to sometimes win and sometimes lose
需要 有时赢， 有时输
but you can't always win sometimes you
但有时你不能总是赢
must fail sometimes you must succeed so
必须失败有时你必须成功
let's see what will happen here yeah so
让我们看看这里会发生什么，是的
it was able to do so the green humanoid
它能够 做到绿色人形
was able to block the ball in a Cell in
能够在一个Cell中阻挡球
a well balanced self play environment
一个平衡的自我游戏环境
petition is always level no matter how
请愿书总是级无论怎样
good you are or how bad you are you have
好你或者你多么糟糕 你有
a competition that makes it exact
一场精确的比赛
exactly of exactly the right challenge
恰好是正确的挑战
for you on one thing here so this video
对你来说，这里有一件事，所以这个视频
shows transfer learning it takes a
显示转学习需要一个
little wrestling humanoid and you take
小摔跤人形和你采取
its friend away and you start applying a
它的朋友 ，你开始申请一个
big large random forces on it and you
它和你的大型随机力量
see if it can maintain its balance and
看它是否能保持其平衡 ，
the answer turns out to be but yes it
答案结果证明 是，但是是的
can because it's been trained against an
可以， 因为它已被训练对抗
opponent it pushes it and so that's why
对手推它，所以这就是原因
even if it doesn't understand where the
即使它不明白在哪里
fresh force is being applied on it it's
它被应用生力军 它
still able to balance itself so this is
仍然能够平衡自己，所以这是
one potentially attractive feature of
一个潜在的吸引人的特征
subway environments that you could learn
你可以学习的地铁环境
a certain broad set of skills although
虽然有一定的 技能
it's real hard to control the square the
它是真实的难以 控制 的方
skills will be and so the biggest open
技能将是最大的开放
question with this research is how do
这项研究的问题是怎么做的
you learn agents in a software
你在 软件中 学习代理
environment such that they do whatever
环境使他们做任何事情
they do but then they are able to solve
他们这样做但他们 能够解决
a battery of tasks that is useful for us
一系列对我们有用的任务
that is explicitly specified externally
在外部明确指定
yeah I also want to want to highlight
是啊， 我也想 希望 突出
one attribute of self play environments
自我游戏环境的一个属性
that we've observed in our dota BOTS and
我们在我们的dota BOTS 和
that is that we've seen a very rapid
那是我们看到的非常迅速
increase in the competence of the bots
增加 机器人 的能力
so over the period over the course of
所以在整个过程中
maybe five months we've seen the bots go
也许五个月我们看到 机器人走了
from playing totally randomly all the
从完全随机玩全部
way to the world champion and the reason
通往世界冠军的道路和原因
for that is that once you have a self
因为那是 一旦你有了自我
play environment if we put compute into
如果我们把计算机 放入播放环境
it you turn it into data self play
你把它变成数据 自我发挥
allows you to turn compute into data and
允许您将计算转换为数据和
I think you will see a lot more of that
我想你会看到更多 的东西
as being an extremely important thing to
作为一个非常重要的 事情
be able to turn compute into essentially
能够将计算变成基本上
data generalization simply because the
数据泛化只是因为
speed of neural net processors will
神经网络处理器的 速度 会
increase very dramatically over the next
在接下来的几天里会非常显着
few years so neural net cycles will be
几年 如此神经网络周期将是
cheap and it will be important to make
便宜，这将是重要的
use of this new of newly-found
使用这个新 发现 的 新
overabundance of cycles
周期过多
I also want to talk a little bit about
我也想 谈谈 一下
the endgame of the self approach so one
自我 的方法 ，使一个 的残局
thing that we know about the human brain
我们知道 ， 人脑的事
is that it has increased in sized fairly
它的 大小相当大
rapidly over the past two million years
在 过去的两百万年里迅速发展
my theory the reason I think it happened
我的理论我认为它发生 的 原因
is because our ancestors got to a point
是因为我们的祖先达到了一个目的
where the thing that's most important
那里最重要的事情
for your survival is your standing in
为了你的生存 是 你的立场
the tribe and less the tiger and the
部落 而 不是老虎和
lion once the most important thing is
狮子 曾经是最重要的事情
how you deal with those other things
你如何处理其他 事情
which have a large brain then it really
它有一个大脑然后真的
helps to have a slightly larger brain
有助于拥有稍大的大脑
and I think that's what happened and
我认为这是发生了什么 ，
there exists at least one paper from
至少存在一篇论文
science which supports this point of
科学支持这一点
view so apparently there has been
看来显然已经有了
convergent evolution between social apps
社交应用之间的融合演变
and social Birds even though in terms of
和社会鸟类 即使在方面
various behaviors even though the
各种行为即使是
divergence in evolutionary timescale
进化时间尺度上的分歧
between humans and birds has occurred a
人与鸟之间发生过一次
very long time ago and humans and humans
很久以前和人类和人类
apes and humans apes and birds have very
猿和人类的 猿和 鸟类都非常
different brain structure so I think
我认为不同的大脑结构
what should happen if we succeed if we
如果我们 成功，会发生什么
successfully follow the path of this
成功地遵循了这条道路
approach is that you should create a
方法是你应该创建一个
society of agents which will have
将拥有的代理人社会
language and theory of mind negotiation
语言和心理理论谈判
social skills trade economy politics
社会技能贸易经济政治
justice system all these things should
所有这些事情应该是司法系统
happen inside the multi-agent
发生 多剂 内
environment and it will also be some
环境，它也将是一些
alignment issue of how do you make sure
对齐问题，你如何确定
that the agents we learn behave in a way
我们学到的代理人在某种程度上表现得很好
that we want now I want to make a
我们现在 想要的是 想做一个
speculative digression here which is I
这里的投机题外话是我
want to make the following observation
想做出以下观察
if you believe that this kind of society
如果您认为这种 社会
of agents is a plausible place where
代理商是一个合理的地方
truly where the fuller fully general
真正在哪里更充分的一般
intelligence will emerge and if you
智慧将出现，如果你
accept that our experience with the dota
接受我们 对 dota 的体验
BOTS we've seen a very rapid increase in
BOTS我们看到了非常迅速的 增长
competence will carry over once all the
竞争力将延续一旦所有的
details are right if you assume both of
如果你假设两者都是正确的
these conditions then it should follow
这些条件应该遵循
that we should see a very rapid increase
我们应该看到一个非常迅速的增长
in the competence of our agents as they
在 他们的代理人的能力
live in the Society of agents so now
现在住在代理商协会
that we've talked about a potentially
我们已经谈到了潜在的问题
interesting way of increasing the
有趣的增加方式
competence and teachings of an agent's
代理人的 能力和 教诲
social skills and language and a lot of
社交技巧和语言以及很多
things that actually exist in humans as
人类实际存在的东西
well we want to talk a little bit about
还有我们要谈一点点
how you convey goals to agents and the
你如何传达目标，代理和
question of the main goal to eight calls
8个电话 的 主要目标问题
to agents is just a technical problem
代理商只是一个技术问题
but it will be important because it is a
但它很重要因为它是 一个
lot more likely than not that the agents
很多 较有可能 的是 ，代理商
of evil train will eventually be
邪恶的火车终将成为
dramatically smarter than us and this is
比我们聪明得多， 这 是
work by the opening eye safety team by
由开放的眼睛安全团队工作
Paul Christiana at all and others so I'm
保罗克里斯蒂安娜和所有其他人，所以我
just going to show you this video which
只是要告诉你 这个视频 当中
basically explains how the whole thing
基本上 解释了整个事情
works you there is some behavior looking
工作你有一些行为看起来
for and you the human gets to see pairs
因为你和人类会看到对
of behaviors and you simply click on the
行为，你只需点击
one that looks better and after a very
一个看起来更好 ，一个非常好的
modest number of clicks you can get this
您可以获得适度的点击次数
little simulated leg to do back flips
小模拟腿做背翻
and there
有
go picking out the back flips and in
去挑选出 后空翻 和
this to get this specific behavior it
这是为了得到这种特定的行为吧
took about 500 clicks by human
人类花了大约 500次点击
annotators the way it works is that you
注释器的工作方式就是你
take all the so this is a very data
拿走所有 这些 是 非常数据
efficient reinforcement learning
有效的强化学习
algorithm but it is efficient in terms
算法但它在 术语上 是有效的
of rewards and not in terms of the
奖励的，而不是 在条款
environment interactions so what you do
环境互动所以你 做什么
here is that you take all the clicks so
这里要说的是你把所有的点击次数 ，从而
you've got your here is one B here which
你有你的这里是一个B在哪里
is better than other you fit a reward
比其他你更适合奖励
function a numerical reward function to
函数 数值奖励函数
those clicks so you want to fit a reward
这些点击让你想要获得奖励
function which satisfies those clicks
满足 这些点击的功能
clicks and you optimize this reward
点击并 优化 此奖励
function with reinforcement learning and
功能强化学习 和
it actually works so this requires 500
它确实有效，所以这需要 500
bits of information you've also been
你也曾经有过一些信息
able to train lots of Atari games using
能 培养大量的Atari游戏是 使用
several thousand bits of information so
几千条 信息如此
in all these cases you had human and
在所有这些情况下，你 有人类 和
human annotators or human judges just
人类注释者或人类法官
like in the previous slide looking at
就像在上一张幻灯片中看到的那样
the pairs of trajectories and clicking
成对的轨迹和点击
on the one that they thought was better
在他们认为 更好的 那个
and here's an example of an unusual goal
这是一个不寻常的目标的例子
where this is a car racing game but the
其中， 这是一个赛车游戏， 但
goal was to ask the the agent to train
目标是要求 代理人进行培训
the white car drive right behind the
白色汽车就在后面
orange car so it's a different goal and
橙色的车， 所以这是一个不同的目标和
it was very straightforward to
这非常简单
communicate this goal using this
用这个来传达这个目标
approach so then to finish off alignment
接近然后完成对齐
is a technical problem it has to be
它必须是一个技术问题
solved but of course the determination
解决但当然是决心
of the correct goals we want array
我们想要数组的正确目标
assistance the systems to have will be a
协助 系统将 是一个
very challenging political problem and
极具挑战性的政治问题和
on this note I want to thank you so much
在这个笔记上我 非常 感谢你
for your attention and I just want to
您的 关注，我只是想
say that will be a happy hour at
说这将是一个欢乐时光
Cambridge Brewing Company at 8:45 if you
剑桥酿酒公司在8:45 如果你
want to chat more about AI and other
想要更多关于AI和其他人的聊天
topics please come by I think that
主题请来我认为
deserves an applause
值得掌声
so back propagation is a or neural
所以反向传播是一种神经
networks of bio-inspired but back
生物启发但回归的网络
propagation doesn't look as though it's
传播不看，就好像它是
what's going on in the brain because
大脑里发生了什么事， 因为
signals in the brain go one direction
大脑中的信号向一个方向发展
down the axons whereas back propagation
沿着轴突向后传播
requires the errors to be propagated
要求传播错误
back up the the wires so can you just
备份电线所以你可以
talk a little bit about that whole
说一下关于整个
situation where it looks as the brain is
情况看起来那么 大脑
doing something a bit different than our
做一些与我们不同的事情
highly successful algorithms our
我们非常成功的算法
algorithm is going to be improved once
算法将是一次提高
we figure out what the brain is doing or
我们弄清楚大脑正在做什么或做什么
is the brain really sending signals back
是大脑真正发回信号
even though it's got no obvious way of
即使它有没有明显的方法
doing that what's what's happening in
做到这一点正在发生的事情
that area so that's a great question so
该区域 所以这是一个很大的 问题， 所以
first of all I'll say that the true
首先我会说真的
answer is that the honest answer is that
答案是诚实的答案就是这样
I don't know but I have opinions and so
我不知道，但 我有意见等等
I'll say two things
我会说两件事
but first of all given that look if you
但首先考虑一下 ， 看看 你
agree if we agree like so rather it is a
同意如果我们同意这样而不是它是一个
true fact the back propagation solves
反向传播解决了这个问题
the problem of circuit search this
电路搜索的问题
problem feels like an extremely
问题感觉非常好
fundamental problem and for this reason
基本问题， 也是出于这个 原因
I think that it's unlikely to go away
我认为它不太可能 消失
now you also write that the brain
现在你 也写出 了大脑
doesn't obviously do back propagation
显然没有反向传播
although they've been multiple proposals
虽然他们有多个提案
of how it could be how it could be doing
它可能是怎么做的
them for example there's been a work by
例如 ， 他们 有一份工作
Tim little crap and others where they've
蒂姆小垃圾和其他他们在哪里
shown that if you use that it's possible
表明，如果你使用 它是可能的
to learn a different set of connections
学习一组不同的联系
but can be used for the backward pass
但可以用于向后 传球
and that can result in successful
这可以导致成功
learning now the reason this hasn't been
现在学习这个原因还没有
like really pushed to the limit by
就像真的被推到了极限
practitioners is because they say well I
从业者是因为他们说我好
got TF to the gradients I'm just not
得到TF渐变我不是
going to worry about it but you are
要担心它，但 你是
right this is an important issue and you
正确的，这是 一个重要的问题 ，你
know one of two things is going to
知道要做的两件事之一
happen so my personal opinion is that
发生这样的，我的个人 意见是
back propagation is just going to stay
反向传播只会留下来
with us till the very end and will
和我们一起直到 最后并将会
actually build fully human level and
实际上建立了完全人的水平和
beyond systems before we understand how
在我们理解之前，超越系统
the brain does what it does so that's
大脑做它做的事情就是这样
what I believe but of course it is a
我相信什么但当然是一个
difference that has to be acknowledged
不同之处在于 必须承认
okay thank you do you think it was a
好的，谢谢你，你认为这是一个
fair matchup for the dota bot and that
dota机器人的公平对决和那个
person given the constraints of the
受到约束的人
system so I'd say that like the biggest
系统， 所以我会说， 像最大的
advantage computers have in games like
计算机在游戏中的优势
this like one of the big advantages is
这就像是一个很大的优点
that they obviously have a better
他们显然有更好的表现
reaction time although in DotA in
反应时间虽然在DotA中
particular the number of clicks per
特别是每次点击次数
second over the top players is fairly
排名第二的球员是公平的
small which is different from Starcraft
小星星与星际争霸不同
so in Starcraft stuff up is a very
所以在星际争霸中的 东西是非常的
compact mechanically heavy game because
紧凑的机械重型游戏因为
of a large number of units and so the
大量的单位等等
top players that is click all the time
一直点击的顶级玩家
in DotA every player controls just one
在DotA中，每个玩家 只 控制 一个
hero and so that greatly reduces the
英雄等大大 减少了
total number of actions they need to
他们 需要 采取的行动总数
make now still precision matters I think
我认为现在仍然是精确的问题
that will discover that but what I think
那 会发现但我的想法
it'll really happen is if you'll
它真的会发生，如果你会
discover that computers have the
发现计算机有
advantage in any domain or rather every
在任何领域或相当的每个领域的优势
domain not yet so do you think that the
域还没有 这样做，你认为
emergent behaviors from the agent were
代理人的紧急行为是
actually kind of directed because the
实际上有点直接因为
constraints already kinda in place like
约束已经 有点像了
so it was kind of forced discover those
所以有点强迫发现那些
or do you think that like that was
或者你认为这样 是
actually something quite novel that like
实际上是一些非常新颖的东西
wow it actually discovered these on its
哇它实际上发现了它们
own like you didn't actually am biased
自己喜欢你实际上并没有偏见
towards constraining it so it's
如此限制它
definitely discover new strategies and I
绝对发现新策略和我
can share an anecdote where our tester
可以分享我们的测试人员的轶事
we have a probe which would test the
我们有一个探测器 可以测试
bots and he played against for a long
机器人和他打了很长时间
time and the bots would do all kinds of
时间和机器人会做各种各样的
things against the player the human
反对玩家的事情
player which were effective then at some
那些在某些方面有效的球员
point that Pro decided to play against
Pro决定与之对抗
the better plot Pro and he decided to
更好的情节Pro和他决定
imitate one of the things that the bot
模仿机器人的东西之一
was doing and this image but by
正在做和这个形象，但通过
imitating if he was able to defeat a
模仿他是否能够击败一个人
better pro so I think I think the
更好的职业，所以我认为 我认为
strategy discovers are real and so like
战略发现是真实的，所以喜欢
it means that like this very real
这意味着像这样非常真实
transformative Tran you know I would say
变形的Tran你 知道我会说
I think what that means is that he
我认为 这意味着 他
because the strategies discovered by the
因为发现的策略
bot of the humans it means that we like
人类的机器人意味着我们喜欢
a fundamental game plays deeply related
一个基本的游戏剧本深深相关
for a long time now I've heard that the
现在很长一段时间我听说了
objective of reinforcement learning is
强化学习的目标是
to determine a policy that chooses an
确定选择的政策
action to maximize the expected reward
最大化预期奖励的行动
which is what you said earlier would you
这就是你之前说过的 话
ever want to look at the standard
曾经想要看标准
deviation of possible rewards does that
可能的奖励偏差就是 这样
even make sense yeah I mean I think for
甚至是有意义的，是的， 我的意思是我想的
sure I think it's a really application
我确定这是一个真正的应用程序
dependent one of the reasons to maximize
依赖的最大化原因之一
the expected reward it's because it's
预期的 奖励 是因为它是
easier to design algorithms for it
更容易为它设计算法
so you write down this equation the
所以你写下这个等式了
formula you do a little bit of
公式你做了一点点
derivation you get something which
推导你得到的东西
amounts to a nice-looking algorithm now
现在相当于一个漂亮的算法
I think there exist like really there
我觉得那里确实存在
exist applications where you'd never
存在你永远不会的应用程序
want to make mistakes and you want to
你想 犯错误
work on the standard deviation as well
在标准偏差 以及工作
but in practice it seems that the just
但在实践中 似乎 是公正的
looking at the expected reward covers a
看预期的奖励涵盖了一个
large fraction of the B the situation as
的 B 中的情况作为大分数
you'd like to apply this door Thanks
你想 申请这个 登门 致谢
we talked last week about motivations
我们上周谈到了动机
and that has a lot to do with the
这与...有很大 关系
reinforcement and some of the ideas is
强化和一些想法是
that the our motivations are actually
我们的动机实际上就是这样
connection with others and cooperation
与他人联系和合作
and I'm wondering if they're thrown off
而且我想知道他们是否被 抛弃了
and I understand it's very popular to
我知道它非常受欢迎
have the computers play these
让电脑玩这些
competitive games but is there any use
竞争性的游戏， 但有任何用处
in like having an agent self play
喜欢让代理人自己玩
collaboratively collaborative games Yeah
协作合作游戏 是的
right that's an extremely good question
对，这是一个 非常好的 问题
I don't think one place from which we
我不 认为 我们的 一个地方
can get some inspiration is from the
可以得到一些灵感来自于
evolution of cooperation
合作的演变
like I think cooperation like we
就像我认为像我们这样的合作
cooperate ultimately because it's much
最终合作，因为它很多
better for you the person to be
更好的为你的 人是
cooperative than not and so I think what
合作比不，所以我想是什么
should happen
应该发生
if you have a sufficiently open-ended
如果你有足够的开放性
game then cooperation will be the
游戏然后合作将是
winning strategy and so I think we will
赢得战略，所以我想我们会
get cooperation whether we like it or
无论我们喜欢还是喜欢 合作
not Hey
不， 嘿
you mentioned the complexity of this
你提到了这个的复杂性
simulation of friction I was wondering
模拟摩擦 我很疑惑
if you feel that there exists open
如果你觉得存在开放
complexity theoretic problems relevant
复杂性理论问题相关
to relevant to AI or whether it's just a
与AI相关或者它是否只是一个
matter of finding good approximations
找到好的近似值的问题
that humans of the types of problems
人类的问题类型
that humans tend to solve yeah so
人类往往会解决这个问题
complexity theory well like at a very
复杂性理论以及像在一个非常
basic level we know that whatever
基本水平， 我们知道无论如何
algorithm we gonna run is going to run
我们要运行的算法将会 运行
fairly efficiently on some hardware so
在某些硬件上相当有效率
that puts a pretty strict upper bound
这是一个非常严格的上限
and the true complexity of the problems
以及问题的真正复杂性
we're solving but by definition we are
我们正在解决，但根据定义我们 是
solving problems which aren't too hard
解决不 太难的 问题
in a complexity theoretic sense now it
现在在复杂的理论意义上
is also the case that many of the
许多人的情况也是如此
problems so while the overall thing that
问题所以整体 而言
we do is not hard from a complexity
从复杂性来看，我们并不难
theory makes sense and indeed humans
理论是有道理的，甚至是人类
cannot solve np-complete problems in
无法解决np完全问题
general it is true that many of the like
一般情况下很多都是如此
optimization problems that we pose to
我们提出的优化问题
our algorithms are intractable in the
我们的算法难以处理
general case starting from a neural net
从神经网络开始的一般情况
optimization itself it is easy to create
优化本身很容易 创建
a family of data sets for a neural
数据系列为神经
network with a very small number of
网络与极少数
neurons such that find a global optimum
发现全局最优的神经元
is np-complete and so how do we avoid it
是np-complete ，所以我们如何 避免 它
well we just try gradient descent anyway
好吧，我们只是尝试梯度下降
and somehow it works but without
并且它以某种方式工作但没有
question like we cannot we do not solve
我们不能不解决的问题
problems which are truly intractable so
这些问题真正难以处理
I mean I hope this answer the question
我的意思是我希望这回答这个问题
hello
你好
it seems like an important sub-problem
这似乎是一个重要的子问题
on the path towards AGI will be
在走向AGI的道路上
understanding language and the state of
理解语言 和国家
generative language modeling right now
现在生成语言建模
is pretty abysmal what do you think are
非常糟糕你觉得怎么样？
the most productive research
最有成效的研究
trajectories towards generative language
生成语言的轨迹
models so
模特儿
I'll first say that you are completely
我先说你是完全的
correct that the situation with language
用语言纠正这种情况
is still far from great although
还远远虽然很大
progress has been made even without any
即使没有任何 进展 也取得了 进展
particular innovations beyond models
超越模型的特殊创新
that exist today simply scaling up
今天存在只是扩大规模
models that exist today on larger
今天存在的模型更大
datasets is going to go surprisingly far
数据集 将会出人意料地走得太远
not even large datasets but larger and
甚至没有大型数据集，但大 和
deeper models for example if you trained
更深的模型， 例如， 如果你训练
a language model be the thousand layers
语言模型是千层
and it's the same layer I think it's
它和我认为的是同一层
gonna be a pretty amazing language model
将是一个非常惊人的语言模型
like we don't have the cycles for it yet
就像我们还没有 它 的 周期
but to think it will change very soon
但是认为它会 很快 改变
now I also agree with you that there are
现在我也同意你的看法
some fundamental things missing in a
a。缺少一些基本的东西
current understanding of deep learning
目前对深度学习的理解
which prevent us from really solving the
这阻止 我们真正解决问题
problem that we want so I think one of
我们想要的问题所以我 认为其中之一
these problems one of the things that's
这些问题是其中的一个问题
missing is that or that seems like
缺少的是那个 或那个似乎
patently wrong is the fact that we train
我们训练的事实显然是错误的
a model then you stop training the model
一个模型，然后你停止训练 模型
and you freeze it even though it's the
而你冻结它即使它是
training process where the magic really
真正的魔法训练过程
happens but the magic is that if you
发生了， 但神奇的是，如果你
think about it like the training process
把它当作训练过程来考虑一下
is the true general part of the whole of
是整个的真正通用部分
the whole of the whole story because you
整个 故事 的 全部 ，因为 你 的
tends to flow code doesn't care which
倾向于流代码 不关心哪个
data set to optimize it just says
数据集优化它只是说
whatever just give me the data set I
不管只是给我数据集我
don't care which one solve I'll sew them
不关心哪 一个解决 我会缝他们
all
所有
so like the ability to do that feels
所以喜欢这种感觉的能力
really special and I think we are not
非常特别，我想 我们 不是
using it at test time like it's hard to
在测试时 使用它 很难
speculate about like things which you
推测你喜欢的事情
don't know the answer but all I'll say
不知道答案，但我会说
is that simply train bigger deeper
只是简单地训练得更深
language models you'll go surprisingly
语言模型你会惊讶地发现
far scaling up but also doing things
远远扩大但也做事
like training a test them and inference
喜欢训练测试他们和 推断
the test time I think would be another
测试时间我 认为是另一个
important boosts the performance hi
重要的是提升性能
thank you for the talk so it seems like
谢谢你 的谈话，看起来好像
right now another interesting approach
现在是另一个 有趣的方法
to solving reinforcement learning
解决强化学习问题
problems could be to go for the
问题可能 是为了
evolutionary roots using evolutionary
进化根源使用进化论
strategies and although they have they
战略和虽然他们有 他们
their cave Hut's I wanted to know if I'd
他们的洞穴Hut我想知道我是不是
open a I particularly you're working on
打开一个我 尤其是你正在努力
something related and what are what is
相关的东西和什么 是相关的东西
your general opinion on them
你对他们的一般看法
so like at present I believe that
所以就像现在我相信的那样
something evolutionary strategies is not
某种进化策略不是
great for reinforcement learning I think
我认为非常适合强化学习
that normal reinforcement learning
正常的强化学习
algorithms especially with big policies
算法尤其是大政策
are better but I think if you want to
更好，但我想如果你想
evolve a small compact object like like
像一个小型的紧凑物体
a piece of code for example I think that
例如，我认为这是一段代码
would be a place where this would be
将是一个地方，这 将是
seriously was considering but this all
认真考虑但是这一切
you know evolving a beautiful piece of
你知道一个美丽的东西
code is a cool idea hasn't been done yet
代码是一个很酷的想法 还没有 完成
so still a lot of work to be done before
所以仍然有很多工作 前完成
we get there hi thank you so much for
我们到达那里你好感谢你这么 多
coming my question is you mentioned what
来我的问题是你提到了什么
is the right go is a political problem
是正确的去政治问题
so I'm wondering if you can elaborate a
所以我想知道 你是否可以详细说明
bit on that and also what do you think
对此有所了解，你也有什么想法
would be their approach for us to maybe
对我们来说可能是他们的方法
get there well I can't I can't really
到那儿我不能不能真的
comment too much because all the
评论太多，因为 所有的
thoughts that you know we have we now
你知道我们现在拥有的想法
have a few people who are thinking about
有几个人正在考虑
this full-time at opening I I don't have
这个 全职 开放 时间 没有
enough of a super strong opinion to say
足够强烈的意见说
anything too definitive all I can say at
我所能说的一切都太明确了
the very high level is given the size
在非常高的水平 给定 大小
like if you go into the future whenever
就像你何时进入未来一样
soon or late you know whenever it's
很快或者迟到，你知道什么时候
going to happen when you build a
当 你建立一个
computer which can do anything better
可以做得更好的电脑
than a human it will happen because the
它将会发生，而不是人类
brain is physical the impact on society
大脑是物质对社会的影响
is going to be completely massive and
将是完全庞大的
overwhelming it's it's very difficult to
压倒它是非常困难的
imagine even if you try really hard and
想象即使你真的 努力了
I think what it means is that people who
我认为这意味着那些 人
care a lot and that's what I was
关心很多，那就是我
alluding to the fact that this will be
暗示这将 是 一个 事实
something that many people who care
许多人关心的事情
about strongly and like as the impact
关于强烈和喜欢的影响
increases gradually with self-driving
随着自动驾驶逐渐增加
cars more automation I think we will see
汽车更自动化我想我们会看到
a lot more people care do we need to
我们需要 更多的 人关心
have a very accurate model of the
拥有的一个非常精确的模型
physical world and then simulate that in
物理世界然后模拟它
order to have these agents that can
为了拥有这些可以的代理商
eventually come out into the real world
最终出来到现实世界
and do something approaching you know
并做一些接近你的事情
human level intelligence tasks that's a
人类智力任务是 一个
very good question so I think if that
非常好的问题， 所以我想如果 那样
were the case
是这样的
be in trouble and I am very certain that
有麻烦，我非常肯定 ，
it could be avoided so specifically the
它可以特别避免
real answer has to be that look you
真正的答案必须 是看你
learn the problem so we learn to
了解问题所以我们学会了
negotiate you learn to persist you not a
谈判你学会坚持你不是
lots of different useful life lessons in
许多不同的有用的生活课程
the simulation and yes you learn some
模拟，是的，你了解一些
physics too but then you go outside to
物理学， 但你去外面
the real world
现实世界
and you have to start over to some
你 必须 重新开始 一些
extent because many of you are deeply
因为很多人都很深刻
held assumptions will be false in one of
其中一个假设将是假的
the goals so what was that's one reasons
那些目标是什么原因呢？
I care so much about never stopping
我非常关心永不停歇
training you've accumulated your
培训你积累了你的
knowledge now we go into an environment
知识现在我们进入一个环境
for some of your assumptions of valid
对于你的一些 有效 假设
you continue training you try to connect
你继续 训练你尝试连接
the new data to your old data and this
新的数据到您的旧数据， 这
is an important requirement from our
是我们的重要要求
algorithms which is already met to some
一些已经满足的算法
extent but it will have to be met a lot
程度， 但 必须满足 很多
more so that you can take the partial
更多，以便你可以采取部分
knowledge if you've acquired then go in
知识， 如果你已经获得 然后进去
a new situation learn some more
一个新的情况了解更多
literally the example of you go to
字面上你去的例子
school ballon useful things then you go
学校 气球有用的东西然后你去
to work it's not a perfect it's not you
工作它不是 一个完美的 不是你
know you pour your four years of CS and
知道你倒了四年 的CS 和
undergrad is not going to fully prepare
本科生不会做好充分的准备
you for whatever it is you need to know
你不管它是你需要 知道的
it work
这行得通
it will help somewhat you'll be able to
它会帮助你有所就可以
get off the ground but it will be lots
离开地面，但它会很多
of new things you need to learn so
你需要 学习的新东西
that's that's the spirit of it I think
这就是我认为的精神
of a toes of the school one of the
学校的一个的 脚趾
things you mentioned pretty early on in
你提到很早 的 事情
your talk is that one of the limitations
你的演讲是限制之一
of this sort of style of reinforcement
这种加固方式
learning is there's no self-organization
学习是没有 自我组织
so you have to tell it when it did a
所以你必须在它做的时候告诉它
good thing or did a bad thing and that's
好事还是做了坏事 ，这就是
actually a problem in neuroscience is
实际上神经科学的一个问题是
when you're trying to teach a rat to you
当你试图教老鼠给你
know navigate maze you have to
知道导航迷宫你必须
artificially tell it what to do so where
人为地告诉它该做什么
do you see moving forward when we
你看到我们前进了吗？
already have this problem with teaching
教学 已经 有这个问题
you know not necessarily learning but
你知道不一定要学习但是
also teaching so where do you see the
也教你所以你在哪里看到
research moving forward in that respect
研究在 这方面取得 进展
how do you sort of introduce this notion
你怎么样 介绍这个概念
of self-organization so I think without
自我组织所以我想 没有
question one really important thing you
问 一个非常重要的 事情
need to do is to be able to infer the
需要做的是能够 推断出
goals and strategies of other agents by
其他代理人的目标和策略
observing them that's a fundamental
观察它们 是一个基础
skill we need to be able to learn to to
我们需要 能够学会的技能
embed into the agent so if for example
嵌入到 代理 ，所以如果例如
you have two agents one of them is doing
你有两个代理商，其中一个正在做
something and the other agent says well
某事和其他经纪人说得好
that's really cool I want to be able to
这真的很酷，我希望能够
do that too and
也这样做
you go and do that and so I'd say that
你去做那个 ，所以我会说
this is a very important component in
这是一个非常重要的组成部分
terms of second every word oh you see
你看到的 每一个字的第二个词
what they do you infer the reward and
他们做了什么你推断奖励和
now we have a knob which says you see
现在我们有一个旋钮，说你看到了
what they're doing now go and try to do
他们现在正在做什么 去尝试做
the same thing
同一件事情
let's say this this is as far as I know
让我们说这 是据 我所知
as far as I know this is was one of the
据我所知，这是其中之一
important ways in which humans are quite
人类非常重要的方式
different from other animals in way
与其他动物不同
which in the like scale and scope in
在类似的规模和范围
which we copy the behavior of other
我们复制 其他人 的行为
humans might ask a quick follow-up work
人类可能会要求快速的 后续工作
go for it so that's kind of obvious how
为它而努力，这是多么明显的方式
that works in the scope of competition
这在竞争范围内有效
but what about just sort of arbitrary
但是那种武断的呢？
tasks like I'm in a math class for
像我在数学课上的任务
someone and I see someone doing a
某人，我看到有人 在做
problem a particular way and I go that's
问题一个特定的方式，我去 那
a good strategy maybe I should try that
一个好的策略也许我应该尝试一下
out how does that work in a sort of non
这是如何 在某种非工作中发挥作用的
competitive environment so I think that
竞争环境 所以我认为
this will be I think that's going to be
这将是我认为 这 将是
a little bit separate from the
有点分开 了
competitive environment but it will have
竞争环境 但 它会有
to be somehow either way you know
以某种方式 ，你知道 无论哪种 方式
probably baked in maybe volved into the
可能是在烘焙中可能会融入到
system where like if you have other
系统，如果你有其他的喜欢
agents doing things they're generating
代理人做他们正在产生的事情
data which you observe and the only way
你观察到的数据和唯一的方法
to truly make sense of the data that you
真正理解 你 的数据
see is to infer the goal of the agent
看是推断 代理人 的 目标
the strategy their belief state that's
他们的信念所表明的策略
important also for communicating them if
对于沟通他们也很重要
you want to successfully communicate
你想成功 沟通
with someone you have to keep track both
与某人， 你必须 跟踪两个
of their goal and of their belief state
他们的目标和他们的信仰状态
instead of knowledge so I think you will
而不是知识， 所以我想你会
find that there are many I guess
发现有 很多我猜
connections between understanding what
理解什么之间的联系
other agents are doing inferring their
其他代理人正在做推断他们的
goals imitating them and community
模仿他们和社区的目标
successfully communicating them all
成功地将它们全部传达
right let's give in the happy hour a big
对，让我们在欢乐时光中给予一个大的
hand
手
[Applause]
[掌声]
you
您